[
    {
        "question": "The ____ of a process contains temporary data such as function parameters, return addresses, and local variables.",
        "options": ["text section", "data section", "program counter", "stack"],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "A process control block ____.",
        "options": [
            "includes information on the process's state",
            "stores the address of the next instruction to be processed by a different process",
            "determines which process is to be executed next",
            "is an example of a process queue"
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "A process may transition to the Ready state by which of the following actions?",
        "options": [
            "Completion of an I/O event",
            "Awaiting its turn on the CPU",
            "Newly-admitted process",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "The _____________ refers to the number of processes in memory.",
        "options": [
            "process count",
            "long-term scheduler",
            "degree of multiprogramming",
            "CPU scheduler"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "The list of processes waiting for a particular I/O device is called a(n) ____.",
        "options": ["standby queue", "device queue", "ready queue", "interrupt queue"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A _________________ saves the state of the currently running process and restores the state of the next process to run.",
        "options": ["save-and-restore", "state switch", "context switch", "none of the above"],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "When a child process is created, which of the following is a possibility in terms of the execution or address space of the child process?",
        "options": [
            "The child process runs concurrently with the parent.",
            "The child process has a new program loaded into it.",
            "The child is a duplicate of the parent.",
            "All of the above"
        ],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "A process that has terminated, but whose parent has not yet called wait(), is known as a ________ process.",
        "options": ["zombie", "orphan", "terminated", "init"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "The _______ process is assigned as the parent to orphan processes.",
        "options": ["zombie", "init", "main", "renderer"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A new browser process is created by the Chrome browser for every new website that is visited.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
        "options": [
            "Shared memory is typically faster than message passing.",
            "Message passing is typically faster than shared memory.",
            "Message passing is most useful for exchanging large amounts of data.",
            "Shared memory is far more common in operating systems than message passing."
        ],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Shared memory is a more appropriate IPC mechanism than message passing for distributed systems.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "The shared buffer is implemented as a circular array with two logical pointers: in and out. The variable in points to the next free position in the buffer; out points to the first full position in the buffer. The buffer is full when in == out.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A blocking send() and blocking receive() is known as a(n) _________________",
        "options": [
            "synchronized message",
            "rendezvous",
            "blocked message",
            "asynchronous message"
        ],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "In a(n) ____ temporary queue, the sender must always block until the recipient receives the message.",
        "options": ["zero capacity", "variable capacity", "bounded capacity", "unbounded capacity"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Under indirect communication, each process that wants to communicate must explicitly name the recipient or sender of the communication.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": 1
    },
    {
        "question": "A(n) ______________ allows several unrelated processes to use the pipe for communication.",
        "options": ["named pipe", "anonymous pipe", "LIFO", "ordinary pipe"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Which of the following statements is true?",
        "options": [
            "Named pipes do not allow bi-directional communication.",
            "Only the parent and child processes can use named pipes for communication.",
            "Reading and writing to ordinary pipes on both UNIX and Windows systems can be performed like ordinary file I/O.",
            "Named pipes can only be used by communicating processes on the same machine."
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "Named pipes continue to exist in the system after the creating process has terminated.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": 0
    },
    {
        "question": "Imagine that a host with IP address 150.55.66.77 wishes to download a file from the web server at IP address 202.28.15.123. Select a valid socket pair for a connection between this pair of hosts.",
        "options": [
            "150.55.66.77:80 and 202.28.15.123:80",
            "150.55.66.77:150 and 202.28.15.123:80",
            "150.55.66.77:2000 and 202.28.15.123:80",
            "150.55.66.77:80 and 202.28.15.123:3500"
        ],
        "answer": 2
    },
    {
        "question": "When communicating with sockets, a client process initiates a request for a connection and is assigned a port by the host computer. Which of the following would be a valid port assignment for the host computer?",
        "options": ["21", "23", "80", "1625"],
        "answer": 3
    },
    {
        "question": "A socket is identified by an IP address concatenated with a port number.",
        "options": ["True", "False"],
        "answer": 0
    }
]
